this is one of the ways to prove the
pythagorean theorem of c
squared is equal to a squared plus b
squared using four similar triangles
with sides a b
and c we can arrange the four triangles
in such a way
that the hypotenuse side c would be
touching each other
and this would leave us with a big empty
space in between with a side c
we can compute the area of this empty
space as c times c
or c squared now let's rearrange the
same four right triangles but this time
the sides a and b
will be touching each other unlike the
first one which has one big empty space
left
this time we have two small spaces or
two small squares
one and two the area of one square is a
times a
or a squared and the other is b times v
or b squared
since we didn't change the areas of our
right triangles that means that the big
area c
squared is equal to the sum of b squared
plus a squared or the pythagorean
theorem